Are you the transfer student, Aili Kahlua?
你是轉學生 艾里加爾亞
No. I mean, yes.
不… 啊 是
I am Auguste Zelm.
我是奧古斯特 謝姆
The vice president of the student council.
是學生會副會長
I'm here to welcome the transfer student.
由我來迎接轉學生
Can I call you Aili?
我能稱呼你艾里嗎
I look forward to learning from you.
請多指教 呃…
Just call me Auguste.
叫我奧古斯特就行了
The game of Aileen Lauren Dautriche
愛琳 羅倫 多德勒的遊戲
is still not over yet.
尚未結束
Now, the life inside the Boy's Academy.
好 男裝學園生活開始了
I'M A VILLAINOUS DAUGHTER, SO I'M GOING TO KEEP THE LAST BOSS!
《因為是反派大小姐》 《所以養了魔王》
THE VILLAINOUS DAUGHTER DECEIVES HER FIANCE
(反派大小姐欺騙未婚夫)
Master Claude.
庫洛德大人
"ONE MONTH AGO" I've said it many times. Please don't do this.
(一個月前) 我說過多次 請不要這樣
But I'm so tired.
可是我好累
Humans and demons are different. They have so many requests.
人類和魔物不同 要求好多
They always give me a lot of matters to deal with.
總是給我處理一堆麻煩的案子
Why don't you take a break in your room?
那就先回寢室休息一下
Let's do it if you're willing to lie in bed together with me.
妳願意陪我一起躺床休息 那就這麼做吧
I'm going to get angry.
我…我要生氣囉
Keith, why did you come here suddenly?
吉斯 為何突然進來
There's something troublesome.
有件令人困擾的事情
We received a statement
我們收到米爾契塔的魔物代表
from the demon representative of Mirchetta, Ashtart.
阿斯塔蒂給的一封聲明
They seemed to have disobeyed your orders
他們似乎違反您的命令
and started to attack a human village.
開始襲擊人類村莊
Mirchetta.
米爾契塔
If this goes on, Master Claude will be asked to take responsibility.
我認為 再這樣下去 庫洛德大人會被問責
That's a vassal country of Elmir Empire.
那是愛路梅亞王國的屬國
The background of "Regalia of Saints, Demons and Maidens 2",
"聖與魔與少女的雷加利亞2" 的背景舞台
Misha Academy.
迷夏學園
I don't really remember the story
我不記得詳細內容
I only remember the sequel is about how the demons lose their demon king
只知道2是因為魔物們失去魔王
and destroyed the Duchy of Mirchetta.
而毀滅了米爾契塔公國
If the duchy is destroyed, Master Claude will be criticised.
若公國被毀 庫洛德大人必定會被問責
His path of becoming king will also be closed off.
成為國王的康莊之道 也因此封閉
If that happens,
如此一來
"DEATH" I'll end up with another Bad End.
(死亡) 我又會走到BD
I need to think of something to prevent this from happening.
我得想辦法 預防這件事
"We refuse to acknowledge a demon king who has fallen to the Holy Sword Maiden."
"我等無法認同" "墮落於聖劍少女之手的魔王"
"Present the maiden's head to us."
"交出聖劍少女的首級"
"Otherwise, we will take the life of Duke Mirchetta."
"否則 我等將取走" "米爾契塔大公的性命"
Prepare the emergency measures for when demons attack.
立刻準備魔物來襲時的緊急法案
I already have Belzebuth and Almond guarding the village.
是 佩魯賽博特和杏仁 已前往該村莊了
I will ask Jasper to call for a gathering of relief supplies and funds.
我會請加斯帕募集救援物資和資金
As for other measures...
至於其他的對策…
I will become the duke's proxy for the duchy
我當公國的代理大公
until I capture Ashtart myself.
直到我親自抓到阿斯塔蒂為止
The duke seems to be bedridden because of this.
大公似乎因此次事件而臥病在床
Can you do that?
能這麼做嗎
I've made the necessary arrangements.
我已經先私下說好了
Cedric has approved it as well.
塞多利克也贊成
Master Cedric?
塞多利克大人
I have a bad feeling about this.
我有不好的預感
I'll go instead.
這樣吧 我去
No. Their target is you.
不行 他們的目標是妳
I have the Holy Sword.
我有聖劍喔
No demon can stand against me.
魔物不是我的對手
Ashtart is probably aware of that.
阿斯塔蒂應該也知道
He will probably be disguised as a human.
他八成會偽裝成人類而來
That place is an area where they prioritise men compared to women.
那邊的地方文化較重男輕女
It might be the hometown of the Holy Sword Maiden,
雖是聖劍少女的故鄉
The teaching of "Even shouldst thou have secured the world's salvation,
"即便是救世聖女" "也不可忘記女性的義務"
ne'er forget thy duty as a woman." has been deeply rooted in the area.
這番教誨 似乎根深蒂固了
So, it's better for you to stay in the empire.
所以 妳還是留在皇都比較安全
But...
可是…
According to the game's content,
根據遊戲的內容
the fiasco is caused by "Demon Snuff".
此次的騷動 可能是使用了"魔香"導致
"Demon Snuff" is a drug that inhibits the demons' rational thought.
"魔香" 是一種能讓魔物 失去理性的秘藥
It has the same effect on humans and can even make them stronger.
這種秘藥對人類也有相同效果 甚至能加強體能
If that thing is used on Master Claude...
這種東西 若使用在庫洛德大人身上…
No! That's so indecent!
不行 表情太猥褻了
Indecent? Where did that come from?
猥褻…妳從哪得出的結論
Anyway, I'm going as well.
總之 我也要去
I will definitely be of help.
我絕對會幫上忙的
Absolutely not.
我說了 不行
You can use teleport, you don't know how a woman feels when she's being abandoned.
你會瞬間移動 所以不懂女性被丟下的心情
What?
什麼
When you are in Mirchetta,
你在米爾契塔的期間
you are forbidden to use magic to see me.
禁止為了見我而使用魔法
It is a trial for lovers who spend time apart.
這是情侶分隔兩地的考驗
If you can't obey the rule,
若無法遵守規則
I will consider breaking off our engagement!
我會考慮解除婚約
Misha Academy.
迷夏學園
I infiltrated this academy
我之所以潛入學園
to see how much it has progressed like the game does.
是為了確認 情況究竟進行到遊戲的什麼程度
Besides,
另外
the palace that Master Claude will be living at while being the proxy
庫洛德大人代理大公一職時 居住的宮殿
is near.
就近在眼前
It's no joke if I meet him here
萬一我這個應該在王都的人 在街道上遇見他
when I'm supposed to be in the capital.
可不是開玩笑啊
I had father's help so my document will be flawless.
我拜託父親幫忙 文件方面絕無破綻
Just in case, I changed my name
為了以防萬一 不只是姓名
and also my surname.
我連性別都改變了
I told you, I need sugar in my coffee!
說了多少次 咖啡要加糖
Sorry.
對不起…
What are you... What?
你們在幹… 咦
Can't you even do a bit of shopping?
妳連買東西都不會嗎
With you as my fiancee, I'm feeling really...
有妳這種未婚妻 我覺得很丟…
It hurts!
痛痛痛…
That's no way to treat a lady.
對女性一點都不尊重
You runt!
混障東西
Who are you?
你是什麼人
I am Aili Kahlua.
我是艾里 加爾亞
A transfer student.
是轉學生
Hurry and apologise to her.
快點跟她道歉
Are you kidding me? Who'd apologize to a girl?
開什麼玩笑 誰要跟女人道歉
I heard this is a chauvinist academy.
我聽說這所學園重男輕女
Seems like it's worse than I imagined.
看來比我想像的還糟糕
Sorry. I'm not planning to obey the Holy Sword Maiden's teaching.
抱歉 我並不想遵守 聖劍少女的教誨
Come.
來
I advise you break off your engagement with a guy like him.
我勸妳盡快跟這種男人解除婚約
It'll be life-changing.
人生肯定會煥然一新
Excuse me, Miss.
我先失陪了 小姐
You are amazing.
你真有一套
That idiot. I told her to keep a low profile.
那個笨蛋 叮嚀過她要安分點了
This is the student council's office.
這裡就是學生會會辦
Senior Kyle. Senior Walt.
凱魯學長 沃魯特學長
It's rare for both of you to be here.
真難得兩位都在會辦裡
I followed him here since he was hiding from girls.
我看這傢伙正逃離女孩子的包圍 我就跟著他過來了
Stop your nonsense.
不要胡說八道
Auguste. Walt. Kyle.
奧古斯特 沃魯特 凱魯
These three people are the characters who can be tamed in the sequel.
這三人都是"2"的攻略角色
The best ending in the sequel
"2"裡最好的結局
is when Auguste borrowed Lilia's Holy Sword to defeat the last boss.
就是奧古斯特跟莉莉安借聖劍 打倒最終大魔王
Oh. Who is he?
對了 他是誰
Nice to meet you.
初次見面你好
I'm Aili Kahlua, a transfer student.
我是轉學生艾里 加爾亞
You look cute.
長得真可愛
Senior, you're too close.
學長 太近了
You are so slow.
動作真慢
Didn't I ask you to bring him here immediately?
我不是說立刻帶他過來嗎
I've brought him here as soon as possible.
我已經盡快帶來了
President James.
賽姆斯會長
James Charles.
賽姆斯 夏魯路
The Student Council president.
他是學生會會長
The last boss of the sequel.
也是"2"的最終大魔王
I'M A VILLAINOUS DAUGHTER, SO I'M GOING TO KEEP THE LAST BOSS!
《因為是反派大小姐》 《所以養了魔王》
JAMES CHARLES, CV SOMA SAITO MISHA ACADEMY'S STUDENT COUNCIL PRESIDENT
(賽姆斯 夏魯路 CV 齋藤壯馬) (迷夏學園的學生會會長)
SINCE HE IS A HALF DEMON, HE IS BEING PURSUED BY THE DUCHY OF MIRCHETTA.
(由於他是半魔) (所以被米爾契塔公國追殺)
IN "REGALIA OF SAINTS, DEMONS AND MAIDENS 2"
(在聖與魔) (與少女的雷加利亞2中)
HE INHERITED THE DEMON KING'S POSITION AS THE GAME'S LAST BOSS.
(是繼承魔王之名的最終大魔王)
James is a half-demon.
賽姆斯是半魔
He was the prince of the Duchy of Mirchetta.
原是米爾契塔公國的公子
His life has been in threat ever since he was born.
打從出生起 性命就備受威脅
The Duchy's churches always have assassins out to kill him.
公國內的強勢教會 經常派殺手追殺他
When he is backed up into a corner,
他被追到窮途末路
he will declare himself as the Demon King and take revenge on the Duchy.
最後自稱繼承魔王之名 對公國施予反擊
I believe I can definitely stop him from becoming the last boss.
我相信 我一定能阻止他成為最終大魔王
I just need to keep James.
只要飼養賽姆斯就好了
Doing this is also for Master Claude's sake.
這也是為了庫洛德大人
Are you Aili Kahlua?
你就是艾里 加爾亞
You caused trouble on your first day.
剛轉學來就引起騷動
James. It was the other party's fault.
賽姆斯 那件事是對方不對
Students should not be a defender of justice.
不准學生自以為是正義之士
Also, my word is absolute in this academy.
還有在學園裡 我就是絕對
Remember that.
給我記清楚了
This happened to me when I was Cedric's Fiancee.
當塞多利克的未婚妻時 也曾發生過這種事
Excuse me. Are you all right?
請問 你還好嗎
You are from yesterday...
妳是昨天的…
Your name is...
名字是…
Rachel Danis.
我是蕾切爾 達尼斯
Rachel Danis?
蕾切爾 達尼斯
What's wrong with me?
我怎麼了嗎
Sorry. I know someone with the same name. So...
抱歉 我認識同名同姓的人 所以…
I see.
這樣啊…
Rachel, what are you doing?
蕾切爾 妳在幹嘛
Come here!
快點過來
Excuse me.
不好意思
I remember Rachel Danis
我記得蕾切爾 達尼斯
was the villainess of the sequel.
是"2"的反派大小姐
She is giving off a different feeling somehow.
給人的感覺好不一樣喔
You caused a commotion on your first day of transfer
轉學第一天就引起騷動
and didn't even bring your textbook to class.
上課還沒帶課本
You must think you are excellent.
想必你一定很優秀吧
What is the answer to the question on page 137?
第137頁的問題答案是什麼
Correct.
正確答案
You're lucky.
運氣真好
"SELENA, THE ANSWER IS 3" What a relief.
(塞蕾娜 答案是3) 太好了
I still remember the game's heroine's answer.
我還記得遊戲主角說的答案
She is...
她是…
Do you want to give this letter to Auguste?
這封信要給奧古斯特嗎
Yes. Auguste helped me when I made my boyfriend angry.
是的 我惹男朋友生氣時 是奧古斯特協調的
So, I want to thank him.
所以 我想跟他道謝
I understand. If you have problems with your boyfriend again,
我知道了 下次再因男朋友而遇到問題
I will help you break up with him.
我就幫妳提分手吧
Is that possible?
可以嗎
Sure but it's better for you to be strong enough to say it on your own.
可以 不過首先妳得變得 堅強到能自己說出口更好
Just like Lilia, the Holy Sword Maiden.
就像聖劍少女莉莉安那樣
Yes!
好的
The heroine of the sequel, Selena Gilbert.
"2"的主角 塞蕾娜 吉魯貝爾
She idolises
她十分崇拜
Lilia, the Holy Sword Maiden
從平民之女成為男爵千金
who became the baron's daughter from a poor background.
亦是聖劍少女的莉莉安
Aili.
艾里
I heard about the issue with your textbook.
你的課本的事 我都聽說了
Are you all right?
還好嗎
It's nothing much.
那點小事不算什麼
Auguste.
奧古斯特
Let's go home after school today.
放學後一起回去吧
A girl came to me for help just now.
剛才有女孩子跟我傾吐煩惱
It's quite troublesome because it's been happening a lot lately.
最近這些事有點多 真傷腦筋
Let's talk in the student council office.
到學生會會辦去說吧
You'll be in trouble if it causes a misunderstanding, right?
萬一被人誤會 妳也會很困擾吧
They still haven't gone back together?
他們還沒一起回去嗎
Is it because of a low favourability?
是不是好感度太低了
Or is it because the game has yet to progress to that point?
還是因為遊戲內容尚未進行
However, you need to choose your friends well, Auguste.
不過 奧古斯特也要慎選朋友
Those who speak bad about Miss Lilia cannot be trusted.
說莉莉安小姐壞話的人 不可信任
Sorry. She idolises the Holy Sword Maiden.
抱歉 她很崇拜聖劍少女
She even communicates with Miss Lilia through letters.
崇拜到甚至跟莉莉安小姐通信呢
But Miss Lilia is no longer the Holy Sword Maiden.
可是聖劍少女 已經不是莉莉安小姐了吧
Don't say that in front of Serena.
別在塞蕾娜面前說
Aileen Lauren Dautriche
愛琳 羅倫 多德勒
is a villainess.
是少見的反派大小姐
She always makes a fuss about wanting Aileen to return the Holy Sword to Lilia recently.
她最近總是嚷著 要愛琳把聖劍還給莉莉安小姐
Auguste, I'd like to ask you for a favour.
奧古斯特 其實我有件事想拜託你
Master Claude, the members of the protection group are waiting.
庫洛德大人 保護團的人正在等您
It's about the Misha Academy incident.
討論關於迷夏學園的事
I'll be on my way...
我馬上去…
If I send a letter using magic,
用魔法寄這封信
do you think she'll be angry?
她會生氣嗎
It's better to not use magic.
不用魔法應該會比較好喔
I see. Ask Almond to send it for me.
這樣啊 那就拜託杏仁幫我寄出吧
By the way, the prodigal son of Duke Mirchetta
對了 米爾契塔的敗家子
has funnelled a lot of money to a suspicious church again.
又把大筆資金給了可疑的教會
Apparently, he asked them to assassinate his nephew.
據說是委託暗殺外甥
Nephew? Did his late sister has an illegitimate child?
外甥 他已故的姊姊有私生子嗎
Yes. She eloped with a man 20 years ago.
是的 據說她是20年前 跟男方私奔了
The man was a demon.
男方似乎是魔物
They gave birth to a half-demon child.
當時 生下了半魔孩子
The prodigal son is afraid that he will become the next duke.
敗家子擔心外甥被選為下一任大公
He is also quite sure that the nephew is Ashtart.
甚至篤定阿斯塔蒂就是他
He has gone quite mad about it.
現在變得非常神經質
I understand. I'll take note of that.
知道了 我會留意的
What is it? Don't you have something to tell me?
怎麼了 妳有事要跟我說吧
Yes. I want to join the student council immediately.
對 我想立刻加入學生會
Isn't that too obvious?
不是要你別太顯眼嗎
Compared to that, we have a huge problem.
比起這個 發生大事了
Just now, I received Master Claude's letter.
剛才 我收到庫洛德大人的信
Did he find out?
被發現了嗎
No.
沒有
I'm just a stupid man in front of you.
在妳面前 我只是個愚蠢的男人
I can't live on without you.
沒有妳 我就無法活下去
If I lose you, it doesn't matter even if the world gets destroyed.
若失去了妳 世界毀滅也無所謂
You, who is like the goddess,
宛如女神的妳
do you feel the same as me?
是否與我有著相同感受呢
Please forgive me for begging love from you selfishly.
原諒我如此自私跟妳乞求愛
I'm waiting for your reply.
等妳回信
Claude Jeanne Elmir.
庫洛德 夏努 艾路梅亞
For my beloved.
給親愛的妳
How do I reply to a letter like that?
這種信要我怎麼回啦
Put Aili Kahlua in charge of the student council's general duties?
讓艾里 加爾亞擔任學生會的庶務
Adding a transfer student might just be what the student council needs.
讓轉學生加入 是個不錯的刺激
I don't understand the academy well.
我確實不太了解這座學園
Please don't be prejudiced. I believe I will be very useful.
但請別太過先入為主 我相信我能給學生會幫助的
This academy is a "Little Mirchetta"
這座學園就是小型的米爾契塔
and the student council is a mini "government".
學生會就是小型的國務機關
Which idiot will allow a transfer student to join it?
哪個笨蛋會讓外來的轉學生加入
I agree.
我贊成喔
Importing talents is quite common after all.
畢竟拉攏優秀人才是常有的事
It's a good thing to have more allies.
同志增加是件好事
Let me see if you really are an exceptional talent then.
那就讓我確認你是否是優秀人才
What should I do?
我該做什麼
An investigation. A few days ago, a female student was wounded.
調查 前幾天有女學生受了傷
Apparently, the culprit was a vampire.
傳聞是吸血鬼下的毒手
Vampire?
吸血鬼
Is it a demon?
是魔物嗎
The female student was unconscious and there were marks of blood being sucked.
陷入昏睡的女學生 身上有被吸血的痕跡
However, she doesn't remember anything so we don't have much information.
但當事人卻不記得 所以無法知道更多情報
The academy's protection group has gone to the duke's proxy to discuss this.
聽說學園的保護團體 已經去找代理大公討論了
The duke's proxy is...
代理大公是…
The Demon King. How courageous of them.
就是魔王吧 還真有勇氣
I heard they are planning to ask if the culprit is the Demon King.
聽說他們打算逼問 犯人是否是魔王
I accept the investigation.
我接受這項調查
I just need to find the culprit, right?
只要抓到犯人就行了吧
I can't let Master Claude be suspected as the culprit who attacked the student.
我不能接受庫洛德大人 被懷疑是襲擊學生的犯人
I'll leave it to you then.
那就交給你吧
I'll put you in charge of general duties if you resolve this incident.
若你順利解決 就讓你擔任庶務
One more thing.
還有一件事
I'd like you to permit the establishment of a guard unit.
希望會長能允許設立警衛隊
A guard unit?
警衛隊
Since the culprit might be a demon, we will need a guard unit immediately.
既然犯人有可能是魔物 那就該設立警衛隊吧
That's reasonable.
有道理
Regarding the establishment of the guard unit,
那麼關於設立警衛隊一事
Get this document to the principal, the duke's proxy, to sign it.
把這份文件交給學園長 也就是代理大公簽名吧
What?
什麼
The academy's principal is the duke of Mirchetta.
米爾契塔大公兼任本校學園長
So, the principal right now is the duke's proxy.
所以現在代理大公就是學園長
But, that's...
可是 那個…
You will soon be taking on the vampire's case.
你馬上就要挑戰吸血鬼事件了
Are you still afraid of the Demon King?
還會怕魔王嗎
Is there a way to turn Aileen into a bolster?
有沒有什麼方法 能讓愛琳變成抱枕…
I realised this recently.
我最近發現
When my master is exhausted, he turns into a fool for love.
我家主人過度疲勞時 會變成戀愛笨蛋
Oh. The student of the academy will be asking you to sign some documents.
對了 學園的學生 會拿文件來給你簽名
Come in.
進來吧
PLEASE SIGN IT
(請簽名)
Why are you dressed like a duck?
你…為什麼打扮成鴨子
I ESCAPED FROM THE SCHOOL FESTIVAL'S PREPARATION.
(我從學園祭的準備工作空檔中) (跑出來)
So, a student is inside the costume?
裡面是學生吧
I AM JUST A DUCK.
(我只是隻鴨子)
I don't think an ordinary duck can ask me to sign documents.
我不認為普通的鴨子 會拿文件來給我簽名
THE DUCK IS MISHA ACADEMY'S ENVOY
(鴨子是迷夏學園的使者)
The symbol of the academy isn't a duck.
學園的象徵不是鴨子
It should be a lily that represents the Holy Sword Maiden.
應該是象徵聖劍少女的百合花吧
Master Claude! Aileen! Reply! Here!
庫洛德大人 愛琳 回信 來了
I think establishing the guard unit
我認為設立警衛隊
to help assist in investigations and prevent crime is a good idea.
協助調查及阻止憾事發生 是個不錯的提議
Do your best.
加油喔
THANK YOU
(謝謝)
Almond, good boy.
杏仁 乖孩子
I am a capable demon.
本大爺 是能幹的魔物
Dear Master Claude.
親愛的庫洛德大人
I am fine.
我很好
Do your best in your work.
工作加油
Aileen Lauren Dautriche.
愛琳·羅倫 多德勒
Shock him with a duck costume
穿鴨子玩偶服裝讓他動搖
and distract him with my reply.
並用我的回信分散注意力
My strategy was perfect.
我的作戰計畫真完美
This rain has been going on before I finished writing another reply letter.
這陣大雨 直到我重新寫完回信前 都一直下個不停
Seriously. I actually wrote such a disgusting reply letter.
討厭 居然讓我寫那麼噁心的回信
Stop speaking like a girl while wearing a boy's clothes.
妳不要穿著男裝說話像個女人
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Speaking of which, why did you establish a guard unit?
話說回來 為何特地設立警衛隊
To stop any abnormal things from happening.
為了盡快阻止異狀
After all, I'm not sure if the vampire incident is related to Ashtart.
畢竟無法保證 吸血鬼與阿斯塔蒂無關
Rachel?
蕾切爾
The female student you helped on your first day at the academy?
是妳轉學第一天幫助的女學生嗎
I don't have enough money even if I sell the dress.
就算我賣掉禮服 錢也不夠
That guy is...
那個人是…
It's fine if you want me to tell the truth.
要我說出真相也無所謂
You are the culprit of the vampire incident.
妳就是吸血鬼事件的主犯 委託人
No way.
怎麼這樣…
Professor Koenig is the culprit?
原來凱尼教授是犯人啊
Senior Walt, why are you here?
沃魯特學長 你怎麼會在這
A senior can join the guard unit too, right?
學長也能加入警衛隊吧
Oh, who are you?
對了 你是誰
I am Aili's childhood friend.
我是艾里的兒時玩伴
We met each other in the academy through coincidence.
偶然在學園重逢
Anyway, both of them can be confirmed as the culprits.
總之 確認那兩人就是犯人了
If you have no money,
沒錢的話…
you can pay me in another way.
就給我相對應的報酬吧
When you wake up, they'll only think that you are a victim of the vampire incident.
妳醒來後 也只會被認為 受到吸血鬼襲擊吧
Everything is done by demons.
一切都是魔物所為
Isaac, protect Rachel!
艾札克 保護蕾切爾
Sure!
好
Master Aili.
艾里大人…
He is probably going to do something reckless again.
他八成又要亂來了
I didn't expect him to run this far.
沒想到跑到這麼遠的地方
Also, something smells sweet.
而且… 有種甜膩的香味
That man...
那個人…
James?
是賽姆斯
Why has he transformed into a demon already?
為什麼他已經變成魔物了